PROFESSOR: So this algorithm, what
do people use this thing for?
They use it for a lot of stuff.
So pathing and routing problems
are natural for A star.
This actually shows up
in video games a lot.
That's one of the big crossover
points actually between AI
research and video games.
This is a cost sensitive A star variant
that we used in our StarCraft
bot, the Overmind.
We'll see more about that
later in the semester.
There are resource planning problems
where you can have a nice heuristics
that involve ways that you can allocate
the resources that aren't
actually realizable.
Robot motion planning.
Language analysis.
A huge amount of the search in natural
language, which definitely looks
nothing like position planning we're
doing, parse trees or machine
translation or something like that,
speech recognition, A star is used in
all of these things.
And we'll see much later in the
semester how it is this A star
approach can work for things like
speech recognition or machine
translation.
All right, let's see why
this is so successful.
This is Mastermind Pac-Man.
He's going to eat all the
dots in one plan.
He's going to think, and he's going to
think, and he's going to think, and
he's going to execute the entire
plan without replanning.
This is the quickest way of eating all
of the dots and when I click, he's
going to start thinking and at the
bottom you'll see the node counts.
All right, so this is
uniform cost search.
We're going to find the best way to eat
all of these dots, and this is a
small graph.
OK, so he's thinking, thinking,
thinking, thinking, thinking,
thinking, that's a lot.
Thinking.
Over 9,000.
OK, he eats them.
Optimal path, but took a lot
of thinking to get there.
Over 9,000 nodes expanded.
What about A star?
A star, done.
182 expanded.
Why?
Because A star is telling you, no,
this is crazy, no, this is crazy.
Don't do this, this is crazy.
And so this search tree, you don't go
all the way into the search tree in
every direction, you only do the
things that are making progress
according to the heuristic.
What heuristic works that well?
Well, it's up for you to discover
in your project runs.